Okay, so in this video
then, we are going to cover
just some of the basic
terminology regarding quality.
We're just going to introduce quality and
just talk about some of the important
terms that you really
need to understand before
we delve deep into the
quality management process.
Now, when it comes to quality, we have
to build quality into our product, okay?
I mean, that's a given, I think everybody
understands that.
But in order to build
quality into our product, we
have to build quality into
our entire project process.
So quality does not just refer to quality
of the product.
That's just one part.
In order to have a good quality product,
it also refers to the process.
We have to have a good quality process in
place.
So the quality is the quality of the
product, the quality of the project.
And in order to have a
good quality project, you
have to build quality into
your entire organisation.
So quality management then
refers to following the quality
policies and procedures
of the entire organisation.
Make sure they're incorporated into the
actual project.
And therefore, then, we can have a good
quality product.
When it comes to quality, there are three
actions that you need
to have a good quality.
good understanding of.
And these are the three basic actions
here.
You have a corrective action, a defect
repair, and a preventive action.
And these are known as types of actions.
Now, although we're covering
this in the quality management
section, these three terms
actually span the entire syllabus.
Right.
So it's part of planning.
It's part of executing.
It's part of monitoring controlling.
But, you know, we're
going to introduce these
terms here in the quality
management section.
Now, let's talk about each of these terms
then.
So the first one here, corrective action.
So a corrective action always refers to
fixing the process or the machinery.
Now, the best way to explain this is to
think of an example.
Think of a production line.
In a production line, you've got all of
these machines in a process.
One of those machines breaks down.
We need to fix that machine, or we need to
replace that machine.
That means we have taken a corrective
action.
So corrective action
always refers to the process,
or at least that's the
best way of thinking of it.
It refers to the process.
Something has gone wrong in the process.
So whether it's an automated
process or a manual
process, something has
gone wrong in that process.
So in my example here with the production
line, one of those machines, these
machines, are a process,
one of those machines
breaks down, we need to fix that machine.
Now, corrective action also refers to the
second bullet point bringing future
performance back in line with the project
management plan.
I'll talk about that in just a second.
However, let's just continue.
Now, we've got these machines in a
process.
Each one of these machines is producing
something.
It is producing a product.
It is producing a project component.
Now we need to test that product.
Is that product doing what it's supposed
to be doing?
If it's not doing what it's supposed to be
doing, then we have a defect.
So a defect refers to the product.
Defect always refers to the product.
And now we need to fix that product.
That is a defect repair, also known as
rework.
Defect repair is also known as rework.
Right, so you may see either of those
terms, right?
So whenever you see the term rework,
generally it refers to a defect repair.
And a defect refers to the product.
So corrective action
generally refers to the process,
a defect refers to the
product, not conforming, right?
It's not doing what it's supposed to be
doing.
Now, so preventive action then is you're
trying to prevent an issue from occurring
in the first place, whether
the issue is with a corrective
action or whether the
issue is with a defect, right?
You're trying to prevent an issue from
occurring.
So, regular maintenance of your machines,
for example, is a preventive action
because you are trying to prevent a
corrective action.
Or using good quality raw
materials is a preventive action
because you're trying to
prevent a defect from occurring.
So you're trying to prevent an issue from
occurring in the first place.
So you're trying to prevent
a corrective action or
a defect repair from
occurring in the first place.
However, let's say an issue has occurred
and now we need to fix it.
Whether the issue is
with the process or with
the product, we need to fix that machine.
or we need to fix that product.
So we've got an issue, so we need to fix
it.
We've taken a corrective action,
if it's a process.
Or we need to fix it because it's a defect
with a product.
That's not enough.
Yes, you need to fix the issue.
But then you also need to make sure it
doesn't reoccur again.
So every corrective
action and a defect repair
should be followed
with a preventive action.
So preventive action then is trying to
prevent any deviations from the baseline,
trying to prevent any future deviations
from the baseline.
So first, we want to make sure an issue
doesn't occur.
We want to prevent issues from occurring,
and that's all then, and that's what
refers to building quality in,
and to prevent an issue from occurring.
But if an issue has occurred, we want to
fix that issue by taking a corrective
action or defect group it and then make
sure it doesn't reoccur again.
And that's all part of being proactive.
Now, along with this then,
there are a couple of additional
terms that are very important
on this next slide here.
And that is understanding the difference
between quality control
and quality assurance.
All right.
So what's the difference in between
quality control and quality assurance?
So quality control then refers to testing
the product.
That is quality control.
Testing the product.
Is the product doing what it's supposed to
be doing?
Making sure the product is meeting the
quality requirements.
Whereas quality assurance refers to the
process.
Is a team or rather are the team doing
what they're supposed to be doing?
Are team members following procedures?
Are machines doing what they're supposed
to be doing.
Our procedures being followed.
It's making sure then this project is
adhering to the quality standards,
policies and processes, making sure we're
doing what we're supposed to be doing.
So as a simple example, let's say we've
got 100 scenarios that need to be tested.
So my team has 100 scenarios that need to
be tested.
That's a lot of scenarios.
Testing scenario number one, is this a
pass or fail?
That's quality control.
Testing scenario number two, is this a
pass or fail?
That's quality control.
Making sure that your
team has actually tested
all 100 scenarios will
be quality assurance.
Your team might have
only tested 50 scenarios and
everything looks good so
far and they sign off on testing.
Everything looks good, all right,
we don't need to test anymore.
Happens all the time.
But that's not acceptable, is it?
They've only done 50% of the work.
What about the other 50 scenarios?
What about the other 50% of the work?
So making sure your
team is actually following
procedures, that is quality assurance.
So making sure then quality standards are
being followed, industry standards are
being followed, ISO standards,
6 Sigma standards, right?
When you're building a house, making sure
everything is according to code,
according to the building codes,
and so and so forth.
That is quality assurance.
So again, quality is not just about the
product.
Quality is also about the
process, making sure the
team is doing what they're
supposed to be doing.
And this involves the entire project
process, including things like,
for example, making sure change control
procedures are being followed,
Making sure documentation procedures are
being followed.
Making sure sign-off procedures are being
followed.
That is all part of quality assurance.
Again, making sure procedures are being
followed.
Making sure the standards are being
Again, when you're building
quality into your product, you
have to build quality into
your entire project process.
And so if I go back to the previous slide
again, this bullet point here,
bringing future performance back in line
with a project management plan.
That's where the definition of corrective
action also goes one step further in the
sense that it is looking at
the entire project process, not
just testing the product,
but the entire project process.
So again, quality is not just making sure
that the product is being tested.
That's just one part, but it's looking at
the entire process.
So in this case, essentially we have a
plan, right, where it says bringing future
performance back in line with the project
management plan, right?
So we have a plan,
regardless of whether it's a
budget or the timeline or
the scope, we have a plan.
We see ourselves deviating away from the
plan, right?
So we're going over budget.
We're going behind schedule.
I've seen a whole bunch of scope creep.
Now we're trying to bring our performance
back in line with the plan.
plan, that is also a corrective action,
right?
So bringing the future performance back in
line with the plan.
So we see ourselves deviating away from
the plan.
Now we're trying to bring our performance
back in line with the plan.
That is also a corrective action.
Once we're back in line with the plan,
we want to take a preventive action to
prevent any further deviations from the
baseline.
So again, every corrective
action and a defect
repair should be followed
with a preventive Okay.
So these were a couple of the important
terms.
I mean, there's several important terms
we're going to cover.
But these very basic terms, make sure you
understand the difference
between these terms.
Corrective action, defect repair,
preventive action, and then the difference
between quality control and quality
assurance.